Guide to the Dilip Chitre papers, circa 1960s-2000s.
Chitre, Dilip papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Dilip Chitre papers, 1955-2008
8600
Vijaya. Chitre
1.2
Correspondence, manuscripts, newspapers.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Collection consists of literary papers, including typescripts, manuscripts, publications.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Dilip Purushottam Chitre was a poet and critic who published in Marathi and English in India's post-independence period, as well as a painter and film-maker.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Collection consists of literary papers, including typescripts, manuscripts, publications.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Chitre, Vijaya.; Clearing House.; Bombay Poets Archive.
Subjects:
India -- In literature.; Indic literature (English) -- History and criticism.; Poetry.
Form and Genre Terms:
Criticism, interpretation, etc.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Writing
CONTAINER LIST
- Writing, 1955-2008
  - Songs on Nothing, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Magazines, Date Unknown (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Essay on the Emergency, Date Unknown (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Damn You No. 6, pamphlets, Date Unknown (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Writing on Tukaram, Date Unknown (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Writing on Tukaram, Date Unknown (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Writing on Tukaram, Undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Tukaram Seminar, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - English Poems, 1 of 2, Date Unknown (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - English Poems, 2 of 2, Date Unknown (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Marathi Poetry, 1 of 2, 1955-1960 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Marathi Poetry, 2 of 2, 2000-2008 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Chitre Select Press Clippings, Date Unknown (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Chitre Select Press Clippings, Date Unknown (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Manuscripts & Other Writing, Date Unknown (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Manuscripts, Date Unknown (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - A View from Pune, Date Unknown (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Literary journals (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - A Bio-Bibliography of Dilip Purushottam Chitre, 1997-1990 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Says Tuka: Selected Poemsof Tukaram, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Untitled Poem Collection, Undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
SEPARATED MATERIAL
Books - cataloged individually in the Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections
Dhasal, Namdeo.A Current of Blood, 2007
Sinha, V.K.New Quest, 2004-07-2004-12
Theater Der Klänge.Megalopolis, 2000-2002
Chitre, Dilip.Post Climactic Love Poem, 2005
Chitre, Dilip.Ekuna Kavita, Vol. 1-4, 1992-2016
Chitre, Dilip.Worte des Tukaram, 1999; Two copies included
Chitre, Dilip.Says Tuka-1, 1991
Chitre, Dilip.Sahitya Ani Astitvabhan, Date Unknown
Chitre, Dilip.Godam, 1983; DVD media
Chitre, Dilip.Agatikanche Jagatikikaran, 2010
Divate, Heman.Virus Alert, 2003; Translated by Dilip Chitre
Chitre, Dilip.Der Banyanbaum, 2006
Chitre, Dilip.Shesha 2008
Stegmüller, Henning; Chitre, Dilip; Dhasal, Namdeo.Bombay - Mumbai 1996